Register of the Karol Poznanski Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Karol Poznanski papers,
1918-1975
95014
Poznanski, Karol, 1893-1972
9 manuscript boxes (3.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, diary, speeches and writings, memoranda, reports, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Polish foreign relations, especially with France and Great Britain, during the interwar period, and to Allied diplomacy and the Polish government in exile during World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1995.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (11 reels).
Accruals
Increments may have been received since this finding aid was prepared. Please check Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat to find the full extent of the collection.
Biographical Note
1893 Born, Warsaw
1913-1919 Studied law in Paris as well as in Geneva and Fribourg in Switzerland
1919 Adviser, Polish Legation, Bern, Switzerland Clerk, Consular Department, Polish Ministry of Foreign Affairs
1920 Volunteer in Polish-Russo War
1920-1921 Expert and Secretary of the delegation to negotiate peace with Soviet Russia, Riga, Latvia
1921 Consular negotiator with Latvia, Estonia and Finland
1922-1927 Chief, Consular Department, Polish Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Warsaw
1922 Member, Polish delegation to negotiate with Germany on Upper Silesia
1922-1923 Expert in Polish-Czechoslovak and Polish-Turkish negotiations
1924 Reporter on Polish consular law
1925 Plenipotentiary delegate to negotiate the Treaty of Friendship and Commerce between Poland and Turkey, Lausanne, Switzerland
1927-1934 Consul General, Paris
1929 Delegate to the League of Nations Conference on Ethnic Minorities
1930-1933 Lecturer on Polish consular law, Warsaw
1934-1945 Consul General, London
1943-1945 Deputy director and director, Diplomatic-Consular Course, London
1943-1950 Expert in inheritance law
1945-1947 Section head, Interim Treasury Committee for Polish Question
1945-1970 Chairman, Polish Citizens Committee for Refugees
1947-1970 Consultant in Polish and international law, London
1950-1952 Lecturer on comparative consular law and diplomatic service, London
1971 Died, London
Scope and Content Note
Karol Poznanski, diplomat, consul general, teacher, writer and émigré activist was born in partitioned Poland and spent most of his life working abroad in the Polish diplomatic service. Educated as a lawyer, he made a significant contribution to the restoration of Poland's consular network. Being only in his early 30s he became Poland's top expert in international negotiations. He served in the capacity of secretary, legal and plenipotentiary delegate of various Polish delegations, and signed agreements with other countries.
Most of Poznanski's life was spent in Great Britain, where he was appointed Consul General in London in 1934. He remained in this position until 1945, when the British withdrew recognition of the government he represented. Thereafter he kept himself busy in the Polish émigré circles where he provided legal assistance and volunteered in many organizations (some of which he created) such as the former Foreign Service officials, refugees, cultural and professional associations. He also performed the functions of administrator of estates, notary public, translator, and judge.
The various series in this collection reflect the different stages of Poznanski's life, mainly the time he spent in Great Britain. This is true especially of the correspondence series, covering to a small degree the 1930s, as well as late 1960s and early 1970s. The same is true with the subject series. Of particular importance is the conventions and treaties series, which illustrates the significant input Poznanski made in the diplomatic arena. The photographs portray individuals and events of Poland's inter-war diplomatic history.
This collection was acquired by the Hoover Institution in 1995.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Poland--Foreign relations--France.; France--Foreign relations--Poland.; Poland--Foreign relations--Great Britain.; Great Britain--Foreign relations--Poland.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--Governments in exile.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; Poland.; France.; Great Britain.; World War, 1939-1945.; Poland--Foreign relations.
Occupations
Diplomats--Poland.
Series Description
- Biographical File, 1918-1944. (Box 1)
  Certificate, clippings, curriculum vitae, German diplomatic visa, invitations, property records, and visiting cards documenting the life and career of Karol Poznanski, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Memoirs, 1939 August-October (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1929-1970. (Box 1-2)
  Letters arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
- Speeches and Writings, 1929-1951. (Box 2-3)
  Articles, broadcasts, essays relating to Poznanski's consular as well as instructor's career in the diplomatic service and as contributor to Radio Free Europe, arranged chronologically by title
- Conventions and Treaties, 1818-1933. (Box 3-4)
  Agreements, conventions, and treaties signed by Poland with Poznanski's contribution, arranged alphabetically by physical form and therein by country. Includes material relating to Polish law in general
- Subject File, 1929-1975. (Box 4-7)
  Clippings, correspondence, decrees, lists, memoranda, reports, speeches, will, arranged alphabetically by subject
- Printed Matter, 1923-1974. (Box 7-8)
  Brochures, bulletins, pamphlets, periodicals, arranged alphabetically by title
- Photographs, 1920-1940. (Box 9)
  69 prints depicting individuals and events relating to Poland's diplomacy during the inter-war period
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1918-1944 (Box 1)
  - Certificate of professional advancement, 1924 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Clippings, 1918-1929 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Curriculum vitae, n.d. (Folder 1: 3)
  - German diplomatic visa, 1934 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Invitations, 1931-1939., See also CORRESPONDENCE/General/Consular invitations (Folder 1: 5)
  - Personal property record, 1928-1944 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Visiting cards, 1930s (Folder 1: 7)
- MEMOIRS, 1939 August-October. (Folder 1: 8)
  Mimeographed copy
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1929-1970
  - General
    - General
      - 1929 (Folder 1: 9)
      - 1931 (Folder 1: 10)
      - 1932 (Folder 1: 11)
      - 1933 (Folder 1: 12)
      - 1934 (Folder 1: 13)
      - 1935 (Folder 1: 14)
      - 1936 (Folder 1: 15)
      - 1938 (Folder 1: 16)
      - 1945 (Folder 1: 17)
      - 1948 (Folder 1: 18)
      - 1954 (Folder 1: 19)
      - 1963 (Folder 1: 20)
      - 1969 (Folder 1: 21)
      - 1970 (Folder 1: 22)
    - Consular invitations (Box 2)
      - 1934 (Folder 2: 1)
      - 1937 (Folder 2: 2)
      - 1938 (Folder 2: 3)
      - 1939 (Folder 2: 4)
      - 1940 (Folder 2: 5)
  - Cecil, Robert, Lord, 1933 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Czarnecki, Zygmunt, 1966 (Folder 2: 7)
  - Iranek-Osmecki, K. 1969 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Mackiewicz, Jozef, 1969 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Malinowski, T., 1967 (Folder 2: 10)
  - Nowak, Jan, 1956 and 1968 (Folder 2: 11)
  - Raczkiewicz, Wladyslaw, 1930, 1963 (Folder 2: 12)
  - Raczynski, Edward, 1970 (Folder 2: 13)
  - Sabbat, Kazimierz, 1969 (Folder 2: 14)
  - Sikorska, Helena, 1969 (Folder 2: 15)
  - Sosnkowski, Kazimierz, 1967., See also SUBJECT FILE (Folder 2: 16)
  - Szkola Nauk Politycznych I Spolecznych, 1951-1957 (Folder 2: 17)
  - Wieniawa-Dlugoszowski, Boleslaw, 1939-1940 (Folder 2: 18)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1929-1951
  - General, 1936-1945 (Folder 2: 19)
  - Broadcasts for Radio Free Europe, n.d.
    - Nos. 1-25 (Folder 2: 20)
    - Nos. 26-50 (Folder 2: 21)
    - Nos. 51-75 (Folder 2: 22)
    - Nos. 76-109 (Folder 3: 1)
  - "Administracja Konsulatow," 1929. (Folder 3: 2)
    Typescript
  - "Polskie Konwencje Konsularne," 1931. (Folder 3: 3)
  - "Szkola Nauk Politycznych," 1950-1951. (Folder 3: 4)
- CONVENTIONS AND TREATIES, 1818-1933
  - General - Polish laws
    - Association law, 1932 (Folder 3: 5)
    - Citizenship acts of 1920, 1951, 1962 (Folder 3: 6)
    - Citizenship and property law of persons of Jewish origin in pre-war Poland (Folder 3: 7)
    - Consular law
      - General (Folder 3: 8)
      - Interaction of Polish consular agencies and diplomatic representatives, 1933 (Folder 3: 9)
    - Emigration law, 1933 (Folder 3: 10)
    - Inheritance law, 1924 and 1943 (Folder 3: 11)
    - Nationalization decrees and orders, Warsaw, 1946 (Folder 3: 12)
    - New codes of law, 1937 (Folder 3: 13)
    - Property law, 1818 and 1825 (Folder 3: 14)
  - Agreements
    - Germany
      - Countries allied against, 1918 (Folder 3: 15)
      - Soviet Union, 1925 October 12 (Folder 3: 16)
    - Czechoslovakia, 1922 - Legal affairs (Folder 3: 17)
    - Great Britain
      - Prudential Assurance Company - Bank Gospodarstwa Krajowego, 1936-1957 (Folder 3: 18)
      - Trade, 1935 (Folder 3: 19)
  - Conventions (Folder 4)
    - France
      - General, 1925 (Folder 4: 1)
      - Emigration and immigration, 1920 (Folder 4: 2)
      - Nationality and naturalization issues, 1927 (Folder 4: 3)
    - Gdansk (Danzig)
      - General, 1920 (Folder 4: 4)
      - Freedom of transit, 1921 (Folder 4: 5)
    - League of Nations - Treatment of foreigners, 1929-1930
      - General
        - Communiqués and notes (Folder 4: 6)
        - Correspondence (Folder 4: 7)
      - Industrial production taxation system (Folder 4: 8)
    - Soviet Union, 1924 (Folder 4: 9)
  - Treaties
    - Soviet Union and Ukraine
      - Peace
        - Preliminary talks report, 1920 (Folder 4: 10)
        - Text, 1921 (Folder 4: 11)
      - Repatriation, 1920 (Folder 4: 12)
    - Turkey
      - 1923 (Folder 4: 13)
      - 1928 (Folder 4: 14)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1929-1975 (Box 4-7)
  - General, 1931-1965 (Folder 4: 15)
  - Amnesty - Poland, 1956 (Folder 4: 16)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew. Speech to the Congress of Polish Scholars, Scientists, Writers and Artists, 1975 (Folder 4: 17)
  - Budget - Poland, 1953. (Folder 4: 18)
    Includes references to Skarb Narodowy (National Treasury)
  - Cassino (Italy), Battle of 1944 - 10th anniversary, 1954 (Folder 4: 19)
  - Cultural property - Repatriation - Poland.
    Material relating to the royal sword
    - 1951 (Folder 4: 20)
    - 1957 (Folder 4: 21)
    - 1958 (Folder 4: 22)
    - 1959
      - General (Folder 4: 23)
      - Clippings (Folder 4: 24)
    - 1960 (Folder 4: 25)
    - 1961
      - General (Folder 4: 26)
      - Clippings (Folder 4: 27)
    - 1962 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - 1963
      - General (Folder 5: 2)
      - Clippings (Folder 5: 3)
  - Danina Polska, 1954-1957 (Folder 5: 4)
  - Great Britain - Representatives of foreign states and Commonwealth countries in London. Lists, 1950-1954 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Hlond, August, Cardinal (Folder 5: 6)
  - Hochberg, Alexander, Count, 1959-1965 (Folder 5: 7)
  - Hochhuth, Rolf. Clippings on his play "Soldiers," 1967 (Folder 5: 8)
  - Komisja do Rozpatrzenia Spraw Lacznosci z Krajem, 1956 (Folder 5: 9)
  - Komitet Obywatelski Pomocy Uchodzcom Polskim (Polish Citizens Committee for Refugees)
    - General
      - General, 1966 (Folder 5: 10)
      - Clippings, 1964 (Folder 5: 11)
    - Dobek, Czeslaw vs. Kultura, 1964-1966 (Folder 5: 12)
  - Kon, Adolf (Folder 5: 13)
  - Konferencja Ekonomiczna w Sprawach Krajowych, London, 1964 (Folder 5: 14)
  - Misiak Trial, n.d. (Folder 5: 15)
  - Nowak-Jezioranski, Jan. Farewell speech to Radio Free Europe listeners, 1975 (Folder 5: 16)
  - Nowakowski, Tadeusz, 1969 (Folder 5: 17)
  - Poland. Komisja do Spraw Lacznosci z Krajem, 1956 (Folder 5: 18)
  - Poland. Komisja Prac Ustawodawczych przy Ministerstwie Sprawiedliwosci.
    - Courts of Justice, 1944 (Folder 5: 19)
    - State security laws, 1934-1944(?) (Folder 5: 20)
  - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Wewnetrznych (Ministry of Interior). Reports from occupied Poland, 1941., See also Stanczyk, Jan (Folder 5: 21)
    Includes references to Warsaw Ghetto and Auschwitz.
  - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Ministry of Foreign Afairs)
    - Desertion of Jewish soldiers from the Polish Army in Great Britain, 1944 (Folder 5: 22)
    - Minister. Speech, 1953 (Folder 5: 23)
    - Poles abroad - Government policy, 1932-1945 (Folder 5: 24)
  - Poland. Ministerstwo Sprawiedliwosci (Ministry of Justice). Annual report, 1943 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Poland. Premier, 1956 (Folder 6: 2)
  - Poland. Prezydent. Decree on de-legalization of German laws in occupied Poland, 1939-1944 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Poles
    - France
      - 1931 (Folder 6: 4)
      - 1932-1934 (Folder 6: 5)
    - Great Britain
      - General, 1969 (Folder 6: 6)
      - Mental patients, 1949 (Folder 6: 7)
      - Personal estates, 1946 (Folder 6: 8)
      - Polski Osrodek Spoleczno Kulturalny w Londynie
        - 1960-1962 (Folder 6: 9)
        - 1963-1964 (Folder 6: 10)
        - 1965 (Folder 6: 11)
        - 1966 (Folder 6: 12)
        - 1967
          - General (Folder 6: 13)
          - Clippings (Folder 6: 14)
      - Stowarzyszenie Lotnikow Polskich, 1954 (Folder 6: 15)
      - Theater, 1969 (Folder 6: 16)
      - Zrzeszenie Polonii Brytyjskiej, 1961-1967 (Folder 6: 17)
  - Refugees - United Nations ordinance, 1946 (Folder 6: 18)
  - Rzeczpospolita Polska (Government-in-exile)
    - Diplomatic network in Great Britain - Closing of operations in 1945
      - General
        - Correspondence (Folder 6: 19)
        - Memoranda (Folder 6: 20)
        - Printed matter - For Freedom and Independence of Poland,January 1st, 1946 - January 1st, 1947 (Folder 6: 21)
      - Talks with the British (Folder 6: 22)
    - Foreign service (Box 7)
      - Cadre training, 1942-1943 (Folder 7: 1)
      - Network
        - 1929, including in City of Gdansk (Folder 7: 2)
        - 1945 (Folder 7: 3)
  - Sosnkowski, Kazimierz. Last will, 1943 November 3, opened in 1969 (Folder 7: 4)
  - Stanczyk, Jan. Speech to the Anglo-Palestinian Club on the situation of Jews in Poland and in the Warsaw Ghetto in particular, 1941 April 20 (Folder 7: 5)
  - Ussas, Bronislaw Matveievich, Trial of, 1925 (Folder 7: 6)
  - Warsaw Uprising, 1944 (Folder 7: 7)
  - World War, 1939-1945
    - German compensations. Clippings, 1961 (Folder 7: 8)
    - Invasion of Poland, September 1939 - First anniversary in Poland's underground press, 1940 (Folder 7: 9)
    - Refugees from Belgium and the Netherlands in Great Britain, 1940 (Folder 7: 10)
    - Repatriation
      - General, 1932-1945 (Folder 7: 11)
      - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Commission, 1944 (Folder 7: 12)
  - Wyszynski, Stefan, Primate (Folder 7: 13)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1923-1974
  - General. Clippings, 1939-1970 (Folder 7: 14)
  - Conférence internationale pour le traitement des étrangers, Paris, 5 novembre - 5 décembre, 1929, Brussels, 1930 (with personal dedication by the author C. R. Pusta, Estonian Ambassador to France, to Karol Poznanski) (Folder 7: 15)
  - Diariusz Rady Narodowej Rzeczypospolitej Polskiej, Warsaw, 1953 (Folder 7: 16)
  - Dziennik Praw, Warsaw, 1918 (Folder 7: 17)
  - Dziennik Ustaw Polskiej Rzeczypospolitej Ludowej, Warszawa
    - 1945 (Folder 7: 18)
    - 1953 (Folder 7: 19)
  - Dziennik Ustaw Rzeczypospolitej Polskiej, London. Most issues with references to Poland's consular affairs
    - 1923 (Folder 7: 20)
    - 1926. (Folder 7: 21)
      Includes text of consular conventions between Poland and Latvia and Soviet Union from 1924
    - 1928 (Folder 7: 22)
    - 1931 (Folder 7: 23)
    - 1940 (Folder 7: 24)
    - 1941 (Folder 7: 25)
    - 1945 (Folder 7: 26)
    - 1949 (Folder 7: 27)
    - 1950 (Folder 7: 28)
    - 1951 (Folder 7: 29)
    - 1952 (Folder 7: 30)
  - Fakty i Dokumenty Chwili, 1943 March 19 (Folder 7: 31)
  - Hasla Rejestratury Ministerstwa Spraw Zagranicznych, 1933 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Instytut Jozefa Pilsudskiego: Komunikat, no. 72, 1966 (Folder 8: 2)
  - International Economic Conference, Genoa: List of Member Delegations, 1920s(?) (Folder 8: 3)
  - Kalendarz Komitetu Budowy Muzeum Narodowego w Krakowie, 1939 (Folder 8: 4)
  - Kolo Opieki nad Akademikiem Polskim Zagranica, Warsaw, 1931 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Listy do Polakow, New Britain, United States, 1974 (Folder 8: 6)
  - Listy z Londynu, London, 1945 (Folder 8: 7)
  - Ministerstwo Pracy i Opieki Spolecznej: Dzial Rekonstrukcji Socjalnej: Biuletyn Informacyjny, 1945 (Folder 8: 8)
  - Na Antenie: Mowi Rozglosnia Polska Radia Wolna Europa, 1963 (Folder 8: 9)
  - Obywatelstwo Panstwa Polskiego: Systematyczny Zbior Przepisow Prawnych Dotyczacych Nabycia i Utraty Obywatelstwa Polskiego, 1938 (Folder 8: 10)
  - Ostatnia Reforma Amerykanskiej Sluzby Zagranicznej, by S. Gruszka, New York, 1927 (Folder 8: 11)
  - Polak we Francji, 1927 (Folder 8: 12)
  - Political Future of Germany, 1944 (Folder 8: 13)
  - Polska a Protokul w Sprawie Pokojowego Rozwiazywania Sporow Miedzynarodowych: Mowy Ministra Spraw Zagranicznych Dra. Al. Skrzynskiego, Wrzesien-Listopad 1924, 1924 (Folder 8: 14)
  - Polska i Zagranica, 1945 (Folder 8: 15)
  - Polskie Prawo Prywatne, by Roman Kuratowski, 1942 (Folder 8: 16)
  - Polskie Stowarzyszenie Bylych Sowieckich Wiezniow Politycznych: Biuletyn Informacyjny, London, 1953 (Folder 8: 17)
  - Prawo Malzenskie. Dekret z dnia 25 wrzesnia 1945 I Przepisy Wprowadzajace Prawo Malzesnkie. Dekret z dnia 25 Wrzesnia 1945. Z komentarzem, n.d. (Folder 8: 18)
  - Remember the Warsaw Ghetto, London, 1944(?). (Folder 8: 19)
    Brochure issued by the Federation of Polish Jews in Great Britain
  - Samopomoc Lotnicza, London, 1945 (Folder 8: 20)
  - Skrzydla: Wiadomosci ze Swiata, 1967 (Folder 8: 21)
  - Sprawy Polskie, 1948 (Folder 8: 22)
  - Trybuna: Niepodleglosc i Demokracja, London, 1946 (Folder 8: 23)
  - Wiadomosci Zydowskie, London, 1941 (Folder 8: 24)
  - Wiedza i Praca: Biuletyn Informacyjny Komitetu Spolecznego Organizacji Zawodowych, 1946 (Folder 8: 25)
  - Wojsko i Niepodleglosc, 1940 (Folder 8: 26)
  - Zbior Dokumentow, 1934 October. (Folder 8: 27)
    Includes texts of non-agression treaties with Estonia, Latvia and Finland signed by the Soviet Union in 1934
  - Zbior Oswiadczen i Materialow w Sprawach Surowcowo-Kolonialnych: Tekst francuski niektorych enincjacji Polskich, 1937 (Folder 8: 28)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1920-1940 (Box 9)
  - 2 prints depicting individuals and gatherings during Karol Poznanski's diplomatic service in Great Britain (christening of Grom in Dover?), 1930s (Folder 9: 1)
  - 5 prints depicting various individuals or circumstances during Karol Poznanski's consular service in Paris, 1920s and 1930s (Folder 9: 2)
  - 4 prints depicting the interiors of the Consulate General in Paris, including Consuls Tadeusz Borkowski and Karol Poznanski, 1930s (Folder 9: 3)
  - 1 print depicting the opening ceremony of Poland's Consulate in Paris, 1927 (Folder 9: 4)
  - 1 print depicting the staff of the Paris Consulate, 1928 (Folder 9: 5)
  - 1 print depicting Jozef Beck attending a social event in the Royal Castle in Warsaw, 1938 (Folder 9: 6)
  - 5 prints depicting Tadeusz Boy-Zelenski attending social events in Paris, 1928 (Folder 9: 7)
  - 2 prints depicting a reception for Bishop Gawlina, attended by Ambassador Chlapowski and Maria Mickiewicz, Paris, 1928 (Folder 9: 8)
  - 1 print depicting the opening ceremony of Polska Kasa Oszczednosci in Paris, attended by Edward Raczkiewicz, n.d. (Folder 9: 9)
  - 1 print depicting the wife of Ambassador Chlapowski and Consul Poznanski, n.d. (Folder 9: 10)
  - 1 print depicting Ignacy Paderewski in Lille, France, 1920s (Folder 9: 11)
  - 18 prints depicting the ceremony of exhumation and transfer of Juliusz Slowacki's ashes from Paris to Poland, 1927 (Folder 9: 12)
  - 3 prints depicting the skull of Juliusz Slowacki after exhumation, 1927 (Folder 9: 13)
  - 3 prints depicting Polish tennis player Jedrzejewska during a Wimbledon competition, 1935 (Folder 9: 14)
  - 1 print depicting the consecration of the flag of Polish veterans and reservists in France, n.d. (Folder 9: 15)
  - 3 prints depicting consecration of the Jozef Pilsudski Society's flag, 1930 (Folder 9: 16)
  - 1 print depicting senators and members of the Polish Parliament in national costumes during the presidential inauguration ceremony in the Royal Castle, n.d. (Folder 9: 17)
  - 3 prints depicting members of the Polish delegation to Polish-Lithuanian negotiations in Lugano, Switzerland, 1925 (Folder 9: 18)
  - 1 print depicting the personnel of the Polish Consulate in Moscow(?), 1924 (Folder 9: 19)
  - 4 prints depicting delegates to the Polish-Soviet peace negotiations, Riga, Latvia, 1920 (Folder 9: 20)
  - 2 prints depicting Polish parishioners gathered outside of a London church, 1935 (Folder 9: 21)
  - 1 print depicting Polish consuls attending a conference in Paris, 1932 (Folder 9: 22)
  - 2 prints depicting a large group of diplomats(?) attending a dinner party in Paris, 1932 (Folder 9: 23)
  - 1 print depicting girls collecting money for Polish relief on the streets of London, 1940 (Folder 9: 24)
  - 1 print depicting a gathering of scientists(?) outside of Imperial College, London(?) with Marie Curie(?) in the center, late 1920s or early 1930s (Folder 9: 25)
  - 1 print depicting a farewell gathering for Adam Lisiewicz at a train station in Paris, 1928 (Folder 9: 26)
  - 1 print depicting a welcoming party at a Warsaw train station for Chesterton, 1927 April 28 (Folder 9: 27)
  - 1 print depicting a garden event attended by Polish diplomats in Paris(?) and by Olga Boznanska(?) (Folder 9: 28)